I'm looking for something special.
My mom's birthday's coming up.
How you feeling?
Still trying to get the taste of hospital jello out of my mouth.
But the leg's feeling better.
I thought of visiting.
It's okay, I understand.
I've got to go. Bye.
You sure about this?
Just follow the plan, Nathan. Nobody will even know you're there.
You smash, I grab.
It's done.
Do your thing, kid.
Last time Martha was in, she made a point of trying these on.
Did you try anything on that didn't have four numbers in the price?
Well, I just got in some nice costume pieces from a local designer.
Quite unique.
Straight from outer space.
Thanks, but I'll keep looking.
I'll keep looking.
Don't you move.
The police are on their way.
Clark, are you all right?
Lana?
Lana, it's my eyes. I can't see.
How dark quickly.
scene ...
Oh my goodness!
Busin.
Dad, we're back.
Hey Dad!
Hey, listen.
I'll give them the call after arriveitnig.
All right.
Bye.
I made this whole world shine for you.
Yeah, yeah, come on.
Here, honey.
Sit back.
There you go.
Oh, Jonathan.
We have to do something.
Yeah, I know, sweetheart, but what?
Clark's retinas were scarred by that heat burst,
and you saw the doctor.
He was baffled.
He wasn't baffled, Jonathan.
You handcuffed him.
The last time we trusted a doctor,
she sold his blood to Lionel Luther.
Then we'll find someone we can trust.
We cannot risk that.
Clark has lost his sight.
We may have to risk someone learning his secret.
Martha, this is not about Clark's secret.
His powers have now done something that have hurt him.
And I think before we run out and just do something,
we ought to think this whole thing through.
You know what?
Don't I get a vote?
Of course you do, Clark.
I think it may just be a question of time before I get better.
Sweetheart, it could be permanent.
And there's a lot of people who learn to live with disabilities every day.
What's the worst that can happen?
Go to school and walk through a wall?
What do you mean?
College.
I've been pretty good at exams.
I saw one of the drunk.
Was it in EC, then I was down in Truong?
None of that.
How many times can I tell you that?
I said it's been years.
I was with him,
he said he spoke with one of his friends,
he said he had PSA,
I can jump on that thing,
and said no that,
and I said nope.
If he had constantly fell in love with me,
he would,
and if I still avoid him,
if that's the case,
when he does,
it's gonna be hard for me.
Boy, when I'll interview Charles Sayles,
который sまで Gil Chemistry чтобы помiding,
I'd be hyped up over the fact that I had such a hard time with Plain Unfair.
I think Judge Ross is gonna be giving this Masterson guy any breaks.
Clark.
You're already back.
It's nothing quite that heroic.
It's just a pit stop.
Well, if you need anything, I'm here for you.
Class notes, help writing your papers.
One thing I learned from my accident is that you can't go through something like this alone.
Ma, just because I'm blind doesn't mean the issues between us have disappeared.
And this doesn't change anything.
I was just offering a helping hand, Clark.
But I won't make that mistake again.
Laura said absence makes the heart grow fonder.
Obviously hasn't met the two of you.
But I'm sure you'll find something.
Clark, what's the matter?
Pete, did you hear that?
Hello?
Chloe?
She's not here, Clark.
Hello?
Pete, I can hear her right now.
What do you want?
I'm at the store.
This isn't the best place to talk.
I'm done with this.
Someone could hear me.
I can't believe you're calling me, especially after everything that's happened.
Look, I told you before.
My researching Clark days are over.
Really?
I have such a vivid memory of that young reporter, just eager to work for the Daily Planet.
As an opportunity I provided for with only one requirement.
Well, I gave you all the information I had, Mr. Luther.
Well, but you have to look at Clark Kent as a work in progress.
Tell me it didn't arouse your instincts as a journalist when you learned about Clark's blindness.
Especially when the other people at the scene were treated with hearing-related traumas.
Look, you're gonna have to find someone else to connect the dots, Mr. Luther, because I'm done with this.
Huh?
What are you gonna do then?
You gonna go running back to Lexington?
Or what's left of him?
Lex has a serious mental illness.
It's as if there's a crack in his foundation, you understand?
The structure may look perfectly stable, but it can't take any pressure.
So we will let Lex sit in his office sharpening pencils.
But I expect a full report from you on Clark Kent, Ms. Sullivan, by week's end.
What happened?
Pete, there's something wrong.
You have to get me home right away.
So these sounds, they just hit you all at once?
It's like someone turned on a giant stereo full blast.
Suddenly all the sounds are magnified.
There's the couch.
And then they just went away.
It was completely random.
Well, with your X-ray abilities and your heat vision, we're done.
I'm not really sure how your sensors are supposed to develop.
It might just have been a one-time thing.
Or maybe your body's trying to compensate for its lack of sight.
I just hope it goes away.
All the sounds, they were so loud.
I didn't even know where they were coming from or what they were.
But then there was Chloe and Lionel.
What about them?
They must have been on the phone.
They were talking about me.
I don't think it was for the first time either.
Hey.
Oh, Lex.
Boy.
It's nice to see you.
Mr. Kent.
Well, I have to go fill out some paperwork for Clark's principal.
Yeah, stuff's due tomorrow.
Clark, I don't know what to say.
How about hello?
Come on, behind the Ray-Bans, I'm still the same old Clark.
You know, when my father lost his sight, I, uh, I made contact with some of the world's top ophthalmologists.
You just say the word and I can make any one of them available to you.
Well, I appreciate that, Lex, but this isn't a problem to be solved.
This is something I need to learn to live with.
Look, I really don't want to talk about my condition.
Even when people don't mention it, I can hear the concern in their voices.
Trust me.
I know the feeling.
I discovered there's an almost...
medieval prejudice against the survivors of mental illness.
I decided the only way I could put the insinuations behind me is by proving my worth.
How are you gonna do that?
By returning to the Luther Corp.
My father's offered me my old position back.
Lex, do you think that job offer's for real?
Why, Clark?
You know something I don't?
Look, I heard that that job offer's a sham.
Your dad doesn't really think you're better.
So he thinks I'm just gonna sit in my office and twiddle my thumbs?
His exact words were sharpening pencils.
Clark, where did you hear this?
It doesn't matter where I heard it, Lex.
The important thing is you need to be careful.
I sweet-heart.
Hi.
You know, Jonathain, I was thinking.
Maybe we should look into hiring some extra hands.
You look tired. I'm concerned about you.
Oh, Martha.
We're barely making ends meet as it is.
And it won't help if you wind up in a hospital bed.
I'll be all right.
I just need...
I need to catch my breath.
What are you doing?
Board of Education Disability Application
to get ClarkЕНés selected.
to get Clark a special teacher?
His counselor said that he could take all of his regular classes.
Until when?
His life has changed.
And so is yours, but neither one of you will admit it.
Martha.
You both think you're supermen who can do everything alone,
but you can't anymore.
You need to start relying on people.
And so does he.
I'm sorry.
So, I got a letter from the insurance carrier.
Apparently my entire medical bill has been taken care of.
Well, who said all insurance companies are evil?
It wasn't your fault, Lana.
It was mine.
I pushed you into the stall.
I spooked the horse.
Lex, you were...
Crazy?
Not yourself.
Semantics aside,
you got caught in the crossfire trying to help me.
For that, I'm truly sorry.
As much as I appreciate the grand gestures,
you could have just stopped by the town and said hello.
Yeah, well, the grand gestures have always come easier.
I'm sorry I couldn't be there during your rehabilitation,
but I'm sure Clark was more than able to pick up the slack.
Actually, Clark hasn't been around.
We kind of decided that the best way to stop hurting each other
was to stop seeing each other altogether.
Given his new reality, I'm sure he could use your support right now.
But the brave front's just an act, Lana.
My father did the same thing.
Lex, I've tried to reach out to you.
I don't think my presence is going to raise his spirits.
By the way, who's Adam?
I noticed the Talon bill has included some gift basket
sent to him at the Smallville Medical Center.
I'm going to reimburse the shop.
You still haven't answered my question.
He's a good guy.
He's a friend I made in physical therapy.
Oh.
Must have made quite an impression.
Yeah, he did.
Don't be a stranger.
I'm so sorry.
Clark?
Chloe.
Hi.
Oh, fret that,000.
Yeah.
Ooh!
Just give me the cocaine.
Actually, I'm on something of a mission.
Have you seen Pete?
Sorry.
Um...
We were supposed to meet this morning
and double-team on my Daily Planet column.
Did the column Lionel Luther helped you land?
What's that supposed to mean?
I may have lost my sight,
but things are becoming much clearer now.
Exactly how long have you and Lionel been looking into my life?
Since last spring.
The day after Lex's wedding.
When you saw me and Lana together.
Is that why you did this?
Your silence is definite.
What did you give him?
Nothing.
Nothing that he didn't already know.
Then what is he sharing with you?
Nothing.
Believe it or not, Clark, I was just trying to help you.
Oh, by spying on me?
No, by just trying to understand
why he's so intrigued with you.
And if the torch got a few new computers
or you made a name for yourself at Daily Planet,
that was okay, too.
For all the times you accused me of keeping secrets.
How could you do this to me?
I was...
He just...
He caught me at an especially bad time.
And I caved.
I've been trying to get out of it ever since,
but when people like Lionel Luther have you,
they don't want to let go.
You know, I thought that you, out of all people,
would understand making a stupid decision
at a moment of weakness.
But I guess I was wrong.
It's for the best.
It's an important truth.
Do you want to tell me your last bad lines,
as my mother says do not yet,
because you hadcurrently,
yet you tried to help me out of it.
Well, not necessarily.
But you know, I'm pretty shy with my primer,
which is getting in the way today.
I know a daughter's shoes-
Oh, Don.
I see.
I'm leaving, and as a lover,
we should maintain comfort,
which is also your duty,
I hear all the noise.
So you're mega hearing things back.
Suddenly I'm the ultimate eavesdropper.
Did someone follow you?
No.
Why?
Fuck.
Ross, get in the truck.
Pete, what's going on?
Pete.
Seth, get in the truck.
Pete, who is that?
Pete, what's going on?
Talk to me.
Pete!
I'm coming in.
So they didn't find anything by Pete's car?
Nothing helpful.
Sheriff, whoever took Pete made the same sound Clark
heard at the jewelry store.
There has to be a connection.
I understand that, Mrs. Kent.
But frankly, your son's ear witness testimony
isn't much help.
No, it is, to a hell, Sheriff.
It means that Masterson has an accomplice.
And in a town of 45,000 people, Mr. Kent,
that doesn't exactly narrow things down.
No, but I would think it would give you a place to start looking.
Abby?
Judge Ross.
You should be home in case there's a ransom demand.
They just called.
I asked your deputy to bring me straight here.
Is Pete all right?
So far.
Abby.
What do they want?
Masterson's pretrial hearing is tomorrow.
Apparently, his attorney is going to make a motion
to dismiss all charges.
If I don't grant it,
they're going to kill my son.
Oh, my gosh.
Abby.
Clark.
Do you mind telling us what's going on in here?
I'm trying to focus my hearing.
I take it you're not having much luck.
If I don't get a handle on this, I can't save Pete.
Clark.
Judge Ross was at the house.
I know, Dad. I heard.
But playing chicken with the kidnappers is not a good idea.
They're going to kill Pete.
I've got to focus.
Marcus, help me.
All right, let's get to work, then.
Listen for your father's voice.
Okay.
Why Clark concentrate?
Concentrate on my voice.
Dad.
Clark?
Clark.
No, Dad, it's okay.
It's okay. For a second, I can hear you.
It's great. I was barely whispering.
Okay. Let's keep working.
Focus, Mark.
Focus on my voice.
Can you hear me?
Come on.
Good.
Maybe he didn't recognize me.
I don't understand, son. What are we talking about?
Humiliation.
Apparently, it words out that my new position at Luther Corp
will consist of a title and little else.
Oh, that's foolish, son.
I've always wanted you to work with me. You know that.
To do what? Sharpen pencils?
Sharpen pencils.
Lex, please.
Listen to me.
If you thought you could throw me behind a desk and forget about me,
you're making a grave mistake.
Unless, of course, my source is wrong.
It's true, Lex.
I have been disappointed with your performance in the past.
But that's nothing I haven't said to you.
And evidently to anyone who will listen.
Listen.
So I have to keep proving myself, is that it?
Unfortunately, we have to prove ourselves every day.
I've come to accept that.
And in time, so will you.
I hope.
Lex, listen to me.
If someone is trying to drive a wedge between us,
someone we both know,
then that's treachery, son.
If they can't prove themselves, then you won't be able to prove yourself.
Who is the source of yours?
Who were you talking to when you decided to trash me behind my back?
Dad, I'm really worried about Pete.
We've looked everywhere.
Well, we're at town, Clark.
I thought maybe you and I could get an update.
I'll be right back, son.
I was fast.
Your dad told me you were out here.
Lana.
Thought she might want some company.
But if you don't...
No, please stay.
About this morning.
It's okay, Clark. You were upset.
No. It's not okay.
All I've managed to do lately is push people away.
And the truth is, Lana, I miss having you in my life.
But I understand why you don't want me around.
I was hurt and scared.
Clark, I overreacted.
The way I've been treating you, I'm surprised you didn't bolt sooner.
I know you had your reasons for pulling away.
Maybe those reasons are gone.
Maybe.
I'm sorry.
What do you say?
What I'm saying is my life is different now.
And one thing I've realized is I don't want to be alone.
Clark, you...
You're not alone.
I'm sorry.
говорю.
catے I'm sorry.
I should go back inside.
Lana, what is that?
What? The toe snap?
That's the same sound as when Pete...
Pete?
Clark, what's going on?
Lana, this is very important. Go get my dad.
Pete?
Can anybody hear me?
Pete!
Clark!
Clark, help!
Shut up!
Pete!
Pete, where are you?
How's that, blind man?
Come on!
Pete!
Speak with the ones I said.
I could to remove one out of the inflatable,
but should they all be broken off?
Anything but this graduation room.
I know it.
We all shouldn't tell my dad
when he friend is coming home to the identities article.
I don't know if there is any room,
but it makes him say we should get a ignoreprouştel
as soon as he comes home to my ATV.
Quick!
Nothing is statue-inho intestine alright or look in the window.
mahdoll natichen auf rising temperature are normal.
But before we do anything else, there's one stop we have to make.
Clark, come on out.
Sweetie, they look fine.
Yeah?
Yes.
Yeah.
Now, what is your plan?
How are you going to find Pete?
The Masterson hearing is in an hour.
We know he's trying to set up an exchange.
Mrs. Ross lets him go, I'll follow him.
Son, that is such a long shot.
That's all I've got.
Was there any result with the change?
Hmm.
Uh, all right, do it again.
How long will that take?
All right, call me when you're done.
I guess this is the part where I'm supposed to cough suggestively.
You know, I don't have any new information on Clark.
And even if I did, I would have happily emailed it to you,
sans three-hour drive.
Would that have been before or after you spoke to Lex?
What are you talking about?
You know, Miss Sullivan, these coy evasions may work
when you're wheedling information out of the high school librarian,
but up here, you're out of your league.
I'm sure you're not the only one who's been in this situation.
We had what I assumed was a private conversation,
but imagine my surprise to have Lex throw my very own words right back in my face.
You led me to believe, Miss Sullivan,
that you were no longer in communication with Lex.
Well, I'm not.
But thank you for the wildly offensive insinuation.
Al, if you'll excuse me, I'm on a deadline.
Not anymore.
You're coming.
The column at the Daily Planet's been canceled.
What?
All right. All right. Here's the deal.
You tell me everything you fed to Lex, I'll let things stand.
I told you, I'm not Lex's source.
And while I'm sure you could kill my column,
this is not the only piece I'm working on for the Daily Planet.
I know I could interest them in a story
about an eccentric billionaire with an obsessive...
...assessive interest in a Kansas farm boy.
You threatening me?
I'd be careful, Miss Sullivan.
Very careful.
I'll be whatever I want.
Apparently, I don't work for you anymore.
My son's in jail everyой had to hire me.
Coron satu.
I talked to the black.
I'll get to serving by the wrong desk,
but theano couldn't ask for an install.
I know.
I couldn't get out out of there.
But what are you talking about?
Why can't you just leave him alone?
I think I'm in control now,
and sucks.
And everyone should.
It's really vídeo.
Well, hang on, Funk.
I told you I'm in control.
Yes, gall...
Yeah.
Look at him. He knows he has us over a barrel.
What are you gonna do?
Until the hearing starts, pray.
Hello?
Nathan.
Talk to me.
Everything's set. If this judge is smart, I'll be out of here in 20 minutes.
Cool. Then it worked. So what do you want me to do next?
As soon as I'm out, get rid of the Ross kit. That will be his plan to Metropolis.
Done. Ross will be a pile of junk in a minute.
Pete!
Hey, you work here?
What the hell? What are you doing here, Pete?
I'm not working.
Are you blind, man? Where's Pete?
In a minute, neither one of you will care.
Help me!
Can you hear me?
Help!
Pete!
Pete, you okay?
Clark.
Pete.
That's a little dw Vale
I'll be out of here on 12 every night.
Well, you know, what can I say?
Chicks dig a hero.
Uh-huh.
Hope you don't mind I'm bending the truth a little bit.
Pete, look who you're talking to, the master truth bender.
Besides, after everything you've done for me, it's the least I can do.
What's the matter?
My eyes are just adjusting. I think I need a new prescription.
Hey.
Hey, Chloe.
Hey, I'm ready for my big torture interview.
Sorry, Pete. I'm gonna have to reschedule.
I'm really glad you're feeling better.
Chloe, what's the matter?
I just lost my daily plan at college.
What?
Why?
They didn't exactly spell it out on the pink slip.
And in the when it rains it pours category,
my dad just got laid off from his job at Luther Court this morning.
That doesn't make any sense. Your father's worked there for years.
If you want answers, ask Lex. He's the one that dropped the ax.
And one for you.
I just want you to...
Maybe some good news.
Why's Ben count for Bob's a bailiff?
I don't think so.
Because it's me who's been in trouble.
For all of my years as a pre-school theorem nerd,
I've been evenly matched.
I've been in trouble with men and women at backs ofum.
But I'm derechoed to name three.
And I'll keep you safe.
See you tonight, Peter.
I said I could do nothing.
I've accepted my duty as pre-school familiar.
I have a daughter.
heard the gossip and passed it along to you.
No, this isn't right.
It's not about being right.
It's about positioning.
My father won a battle today.
And Chloe's father is a casualty.
True.
But the war is just starting.
And I have the greatest advantage.
He thinks I'm weak.
Frankly, Clark, I thought you'd be relieved.
Why would you think that?
Because at least this way, I was able to keep you out of it.
Looks like you're back to normal.
Hey, Lana.
Um, I'm glad you're here.
I wanted to talk about what happened yesterday in the truck.
Right.
I wanted to talk to you about that, too.
I was way out of line.
I was feeling vulnerable. But I don't expect.
Clark, um.
You know, the reason I pulled away is that I,
I met someone at the hospital.
Oh.
And I'm not sure how I feel about him.
Well, I mean, the fact you're telling me about him
means you already know.
Maybe you're right.
But if, um, if you and I are going to be friends,
I didn't want you to find out from somebody else.
Yeah.
Well, um, I should get back to the Talon.
Hey, Lana.
I'm sorry.
Good.
Thanks for being honest.
Well, that's the only way a relationship can last.
Right?
You are my heart.
You are my soul.
Wherever you are, that's where I go.
Where are you?
You know my ins and outs.
All of my fears and doubts.
Live without
a doubt.
Thank you.